<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

	<properties>
		<title>Who's Using QDox?</title>
		<author email="joew@thoughtworks.com">Joe Walnes</author>
	</properties>

	<body>

		<section name="Who's Using QDox?">

			<table>
				<tr>
					<th>Project</th>
					<th>Description</th>
					<th>How QDox is Used</th>
				</tr>

				<tr>
					<td><nobr><a href="http://www.mockmaker.org">Mock Maker</a></nobr></td>
					<td>
						Mock Maker is a tool for automatically generating mock objects from custom classes to aid in testing the
						untestable. This supports the practises of Test Driven Development and eXtreme Programming.
					</td>
					<td>
						Mock Maker scans the source repository for any class/interface marked with the @mock JavaDoc tag
						and automatically creates the Mock Object for this that matches the class definition.
					</td>
				</tr>

				<tr>
					<td><nobr><a href="http://nanning.sourceforge.net/">Nanning</a></nobr></td>
					<td>
						Nanning is an Aspect Oriented Programming (AOP) toolkit for Java that does not require
						a custom compiler.
					</td>
					<td>
						QDox is used to allow aspects to be applied to classes by specifiying meta-data in doclet tags.
					</td>
				</tr>

				<tr>
					<td><nobr><a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/avalon/phoenix">Phoenix</a></nobr></td>
					<td>
						Avalon-Phoenix is a container for containers or a server for servers that is part of Apache's
						Jakarta project.
					</td>
					<td>
						'MetaGenerate' is part of the Phoenix toolset and picks up @phoenix prefixed JavaDoc tags
						to make XML manifests for the components that will be laced together in more XML to make 
						a complete server application.
					</td>
				</tr>

				<tr>
					<td>QDox</td>
					<td>
						This is QDox!
					</td>
					<td>
						QDox requires QDox to build itself! This is because mock objects are used to test QDox and
						MockMaker (see above) is used to build these (which internally uses QDox). To make this possible, a version
						of qdox.jar is bundled with sourcecode to bootstrap the build process. We do like our own dog food.
					</td>
				</tr>

			</table>
		</section>

	</body>

</document>
